<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>model training on DSLinter - Linter for Machine Learning - Specific Code Smells</title>
    <link>https://hynn01.github.io/dslinter/tags/model-training/</link>
    <description>Recent content in model training on DSLinter - Linter for Machine Learning - Specific Code Smells</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://hynn01.github.io/dslinter/tags/model-training/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Excessive Hyperparameter</title>
      <link>https://hynn01.github.io/dslinter/deprecated/excessive-hyperparameter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hynn01.github.io/dslinter/deprecated/excessive-hyperparameter/</guid>
      <description>Description Excessive hyperparameter precision is a potential risk for overtuning. Overtuning occurs if an overly high precision hyperparameter value allows the model to perform particularly well while values in close range of it do not. Further, the choice of such a hyperparameter might be uninterpretable to users, which leads to an untrustworthy result.
Type Generic
Existing Stage Model Training
Effect Error-prone
Example ### Scikit-Learn from sklearn.naive_bayes import MultinomialN # Violated Code mnb = MultinomialNB(alpha = 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Counterintuitive Hyperparameter</title>
      <link>https://hynn01.github.io/dslinter/deprecated/counterintuitive-hyperparameter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hynn01.github.io/dslinter/deprecated/counterintuitive-hyperparameter/</guid>
      <description>Description Counterintuitive hyperparameters will also cause bugs. There are four posts on StackOverflow discussing where the bug in the program is, and it turns out that a large learning rate causes bugs. This implies that the developer should check whether the hyperparameters stay in the normal range when developing ML applications.
Type Generic
Existing Stage Model Training
Effect Error-prone
Example # TensorFlow import tensorflow as tf # Violated Code optimizer = tf.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Memory not Freed</title>
      <link>https://hynn01.github.io/dslinter/code-smells/memory-not-freed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hynn01.github.io/dslinter/code-smells/memory-not-freed/</guid>
      <description>Description ML application training is memory-consuming, and thus, it is essential to free memory in time. Some APIs are provided to alleviate the run-out-of-memory issue in deep learning libraries. TensorFlow&amp;rsquo;s documentation notes that if the model is created in a loop, it is suggested to use clear\_session() in the loop. Meanwhile, the GitHub repository &amp;ldquo;Pytorch best practice&amp;rdquo; recommends using .detach() to detach the tensor whenever possible. We suggest developers check whether they use these APIs to free the memory whenever possible in their code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deterministic Algorithm Not Used</title>
      <link>https://hynn01.github.io/dslinter/code-smells/deterministic-algorithm-not-used/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hynn01.github.io/dslinter/code-smells/deterministic-algorithm-not-used/</guid>
      <description>Description Some libraries provide APIs for developers to use the deterministic algorithm. Using deterministic algorithms is another effort that can be made to improve reproducibility. In PyTorch, it is suggested to set torch.use_deterministic_algorithms(True) when debugging. However, the application will perform slower if this option is set, so it is suggested not to use it in the deploy stage. Developers should be aware of this setting during the development process.
Type Generic</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Missing the Mask of Invalid Value</title>
      <link>https://hynn01.github.io/dslinter/code-smells/missing-the-mask-of-invalid-value/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hynn01.github.io/dslinter/code-smells/missing-the-mask-of-invalid-value/</guid>
      <description>Description Several posts on Stack Overflow talk about the bugs that are not easy to discover caused by the log parameter approaching zero. In this kind of program, the log function variable turns to zero and raises an error during the training process. However, the error&amp;rsquo;s stack trace did not directly point to the line of code that the bug exist. This kind of problem is not easy to debug and might take a long training time to find.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Matrix Multiplication API Misused</title>
      <link>https://hynn01.github.io/dslinter/code-smells/matrix-multiplication-api-misused/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hynn01.github.io/dslinter/code-smells/matrix-multiplication-api-misused/</guid>
      <description>Description np.matmul() in Numpy library is more readable than np.dot() in the semantic way. Whilenp.dot() provides heterogeneous behaviors depending on the shape of the data, np.matmul() behaves in a consistent way. When the multiply operation is performed on two-dimension matrixes, two APIs give a same result. However, np.matmul() is preferred than np.dot() for its clear semantic.
Type API Specific
Existing Stage Model Training
Effect Readability
Example ### NumPy import numpy as np a = [[1, 0], [0, 1]] b = [[4, 1], [2, 2]] - np.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Initialization Order Misused</title>
      <link>https://hynn01.github.io/dslinter/deprecated/initialization-order-misused/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hynn01.github.io/dslinter/deprecated/initialization-order-misused/</guid>
      <description>Description The AdamOptimizer class in the TensorFlow creates additional variables named &amp;ldquo;slots&amp;rdquo;. The variables must be initialized before training the model. Therefore, if the developer call initialize_all_variables() before calling AdamOptimizer and does not call the initializer afterward, the variables created by AdamOptimizer will not be initialized and might cause an error.
Type API Specific
Existing Stage Model Training
Effect Error-prone
Example ### TensorFlow import tensorflow as tf # Violated Code init = tf.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Train Eval Mode Improper Toggling</title>
      <link>https://hynn01.github.io/dslinter/code-smells/train-eval-mode-improper-toggling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hynn01.github.io/dslinter/code-smells/train-eval-mode-improper-toggling/</guid>
      <description>Description In PyTorch, calling .eval() means we are going into the evaluation mode and the Dropout layer will be deactivated. If the training mode did not toggle back in time, the Dropout layer would not be used in some data training and thus affect the training result. Therefore, we suggest to &amp;ldquo;have the training mode set as close as possible to the inference step to avoid forgetting to set it&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zero_grad Not Used Before Backward</title>
      <link>https://hynn01.github.io/dslinter/code-smells/zero_grad-not-used-before-backward/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hynn01.github.io/dslinter/code-smells/zero_grad-not-used-before-backward/</guid>
      <description>Description Developers should use optimizer.zero_grad(), loss_fn.backward(), optimizer.step() together and should be forget to use optimizer.zero_grad() before loss_fn.backward(). optimizer.zero_grad() clears the old gradients from last step. If this API is not used, the gradients will be accumulated from all loss.backward() calls and it will lead to the gradient explosion, which fails the training.
Type API Specific
Existing Stage Model Training
Effect Error-prone
Example # PyTorch # 1. Load and normalize CIFAR10 import torch import torchvision import torchvision.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Loss API Misused</title>
      <link>https://hynn01.github.io/dslinter/code-smells/loss-api-misused/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hynn01.github.io/dslinter/code-smells/loss-api-misused/</guid>
      <description>Description Different loss APIs take different input formats, but the difference is not clarified in some documentations, so it is easy to misuse. For example, in PyTorch, the NLLLoss takes the output of LogSoftmax as the input. If the input given to NLLLoss has not been processed by LogSoftmax, it might lead to a wrong result.
Type API Specific
Existing Stage Model Training
Effect Error-prone
Example ### PyTorch import torch.nn as nn import torch + m = nn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Initialize Weight to a Constant</title>
      <link>https://hynn01.github.io/dslinter/deprecated/initialize-weight-to-zero/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hynn01.github.io/dslinter/deprecated/initialize-weight-to-zero/</guid>
      <description>Description In neural network, if all the weights are initialized to a constant, i.e., all the neurons starts with the same weight, all the neurons will follow the same gradient during the backward propagation update. As a result, neurons will learn same features in each iterations. In this way, the nueral netwok will provide a poor result.
Type Generic
Existing Stage Model Training
Effect Error-prone
Example # https://github.com/aladdinpersson/Machine-Learning-Collection/blob/a2ee9271b5280be6994660c7982d0f44c67c3b63/ML/Projects/Exploring_MNIST/networks/lenet.py import torch import torch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Missing Regularization</title>
      <link>https://hynn01.github.io/dslinter/deprecated/missing-regularization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hynn01.github.io/dslinter/deprecated/missing-regularization/</guid>
      <description>Description In deep learning, regularization can help control overfitting, speed up the training process by dealing with noise and outliers. Developers should check whether they are able to make use of regularization to improve performance.
Type Generic
Existing Stage Model Training
Effect Efficiency
Example ### TensorFlow # Violated Code layer = tf.keras.layers.Dense( 5, input_dim=5, kernel_initializer=&amp;#39;ones&amp;#39;, kernel_regularizer=tf.keras.regularizers.L1(0.01), activity_regularizer=tf.keras.regularizers.L2(0.01)) # Recommended Fix layer = tf.keras.layers.Dense( 5, input_dim=5, kernel_initializer=&amp;#39;ones&amp;#39;) ### PyTorch # Violated Code optimizer = torch.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
